When I was a child, I was so poor that each meal was just plain rice with a bit of salt.
Every day I had to carry water for people at the market to earn a few coins for food.
I came home when everyone else was already asleep.
I studied alone under a dim oil lamp, the words blurry and faint.
But I never stopped dreaming.
Others would say, we haven't even got food.
What's the point of studying?
I only knew one thing.
If I didn't study, my life would forever revolve around that bucket of water.
I would never rise above it.
Eventually, I scored high enough to get into a top school.
When I set foot in the city, looking back at the road I had walked, I didn't feel proud.
Because I knew as a child, I wasn't smarter than anyone else.
I was just luckier than many.
I didn't give up.
If you want to climb a high mountain, you must be willing to endure the climb.
No one can succeed for you.